# **Prateek Chatterjee**

prateekpc.ux@gmail.com - 508-471-0199 - Portfolio - LinkedIn - YouTube - Arlington, VA

I am a Senior UX Designer with five years of experience helping clients across the Federal Gov., Healthcare, Telecom, Automotive and Consulting industries. I am passionate about designing experiences that are accessible, useful, meaningful & which people enjoy using.

## **Work Experience**

### Senior Product Designer - CGI Inc. | March 2022 - May 2023

- Responsible for managing CGI's relationship with nation's 5th largest telecom ILEC by leading research & design sessions with VP and Marketing team across 13 design sprints. The focus was on increasing customer acquisition while reducing customer attrition through improved CX with launch of new products.
- Helped them get their brand online by migrating around 50+ exiting Lumen.com and Centurylink.com
  pages & content to the new Brightspeed Business experience with limited resources and very tight
  deadline. Ideated and designed 15+ new AEM components to meet the new design needs in Sketch.
- The google <u>analytics report</u> show that there are more that **47% increase** in page views, with over **45% increase** in unique pageviews, and a whopping **70% decrease in bounce rate**.
- Led meetings with developers to understand the limitations of coding in Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) and provided coding feedback for ways to develop the components with limited time, constraints & efforts.
- Converted and migrated old design system and components from Sketch to Figma and redesigned a new
  design system consisting of new guidelines, font system, color usage, buttons and other components
  across 3 breakpoints (Desktop, Tablet and Mobile) for consistency, reusability and new use cases.
- I paired with 4 designers as a part of workshop to design a VR experience where users can practice high stress social tasks to build skills and confidence. The initiative was to help CGI venture into XR industries.

### UX/UI Designer - Softrams LLC. | March 2019 - April 2022

- Led the research & design of new modules in <u>ACO Management System Medicare Shared Savings</u>
   <u>Program</u>, a Federal agency healthcare product. Designed new modules on the existing system and worked with CMS clients and end users to establish product vision and MVP features.
- Re-designed existing modules with UX research methods, also advocated for clear UX writing and 508 compliance testing (accessibility) using wave/web-aim tools. According to the <u>latest performance</u>, ACO-MS had a record year in 2019, in which users saved **\$1.2 Billion in Medicare** as compared to \$739 in 2018.
- Carried out UX Research/Design for high profile business contract, which resulted in a \$37 million program.
- Designed a file sharing and storing healthcare secure SaaS app (<u>Hdrive</u>) based on Google Material design.
   Validated design solutions by facilitating user personas, competitive analysis, wireframing, card sorting for requirement gathering, information architecture and high-fidelity prototypes.

## UX/UI & Web Developer - Carmaguys LLC. (Co-op) | July 2018 - Dec 2018

• Engaged with developers, stakeholders to re-design appointment & scheduling-based application for car service & repair website.

#### **Skills**

**UX/UI:** Design Systems, Usability Testing, User Research, Prototyping, Wireframing, 508 Compliance, Accessibility, User Flows, Affinity Diagrams, Storyboarding, Information Architecture, Competitive Analysis, A/B Testing, Interaction Design, Card Sorting, Heuristic Evaluation, User Interview & Surveys

Other: UI & Web Development, Graphic Design, 3D Modeling, VR & Game Design, Business analysis

#### **Tools**

**Design:** Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, InVision, Balsamiq, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro, Maya 3D, Unity Engine, Unreal Engine, Mural, Optimal Workshop, Google Docs, Google Analytics, Miro, Microsoft Office

Development: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, ¡Query, JavaScript, C#, NodeJS

#### **Education**

## **Worcester Polytechnic Institute**

Interactive Media and Game Development, Master of Science, 2016 - 2018

## University of Mumbai, India

Computer Engineering, Bachelor of Science, 2011 - 2015

#### **Certifications & Thesis**

- Master's Thesis: UX Research in VR Conducted A/B Tests & developed a car driving simulator to teach driving rules.
- <u>Certified SAFe 5 Practitioner</u> Professional responsible for using Scrum, Kanban, and XP in a SAFe environment.
- <u>User Experience and Interaction for AR/VR/MR/XR</u> Authorized by University of Michigan
- Conduct UX Research and Test Early Subjects Google UX Design Certificate
- Foundation of User Experience (UX) Design Google UX Design Certificate